John J. Tavitas

UX/UI DESIGNER • ART DIRECTOR

Art director turned UX/UI Designer with a desire to focus on product and visual design. Recently acquired a UX/UI certificate from the University of Texas, San Antonio with skills in UX Research, Design Thinking, Prototyping, User Interface Development and Front End Development. After 18 years experience of leading and developing advertising creative in healthcare, finance and retail, I've decided to pursue a path were I can utilize my analytical and creative mindsets to solve problems in the UX world.

EXPERIENCE

- Conceptualize, design, and present marketing campaigns and creative for Product Launches, POS offers, In-Store Branding and other projects
- Provide art and creative direction
- Art direct photo and video shoots
- Lead and mentor creative teams
- Collaborate with designers, lines of businesses, management and executives on various internal and external facing projects
- Develop and maintain working relationships with vendors and ad agencies
- Develop user interview plans, personas and user journeys
- Conduct user interviews and usability testing
- Create and iterate mock-ups and clickable prototypes
- Designed and coded marketing email campaigns and digital assets
- Developed and created CRM mailer print creative that increased ROI by 5%
- Wrote and art directed video and animation creative for social media and internal projects

WORK HISTORY

ART DIRECTOR - Visionworks of America - 2016 - Currently
GRAPHICS COORDINATOR - Archdiocese of San Antonio - 2016 - 2016
SENIOR GRAPHIC DESIGNER - Security Service FCU - 2010 - 2016
SENIOR GRAPHIC DESIGNER - H-E-B Grocery Co. - 2007 - 2010
GRAPHIC DESIGNER - NuPrints - 2004 - 2007

EDUCATION

UX/UI CERTIFICATE PROGRAM - University of Texas, San Antonio, TX **GRAPHIC DESIGN** - San Antonio College, San Antonio, TX **COMPUTER SCIENCE** - St. Mary's University, San Antonio, TX

210.279.5859

SKILLS

Animation

Art Direction

Branding

Conceptual Design

Creative Direction

CSS

Design Thinking

Digital and Print Design

HTML

JavaScript

Usability Testing

User Interface Design

User Journey Mapping

User Research & Personas

....

Wireframing & Prototyping

TOOLS

Adobe After Effects

Adobe Animate

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe InDesign

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe XD

Bootstrap

CodePen

Figma

GitHub

InVision

Miro

Visual Studio Code